[
  {
    "question_number": 1,
    "question": "ردّد:كّرر",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "تزايد:تكاثر (يتكاثر:يتزايد)",
      "سدد:قيض",
      "مشي:وصول",
      "قدّم:علم"
    ],
    "answer": "تزايد:تكاثر (يتكاثر:يتزايد)",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 2,
    "question": "الكف:المنع",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "اليد:القبض(السابق اللاحق)",
      "النور:الضياء",
      "القبض:البسط",
      "شتاء:خريف"
    ],
    "answer": "النور:الضياء",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 3,
    "question": "اصطفاء:اختيار",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "تقريب ترتيب",
      "تحميل:تنزيل",
      "تحفيز:تعزيز",
      "…:تعمق"
    ],
    "answer": "تحفيز:تعزيز",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 4,
    "question": "اجتباء:اصطفاء",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "أدخله:قربه",
      "أعانه:ساعده"
    ],
    "answer": "أعانه:ساعده",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 5,
    "question": "هفوة:زلة",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "حزن:أسى",
      "فرح:تشاؤم"
    ],
    "answer": "حزن:أسى",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 6,
    "question": "هفوة:سقطة",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "عهد:ميثاق"
    ],
    "answer": "عهد:ميثاق",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 7,
    "question": "هفوة:زلة",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "عهد:ميثاق"
    ],
    "answer": "عهد:ميثاق",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 8,
    "question": "سحَب:جذب",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "كسر:فلق",
      "نوم:راحة"
    ],
    "answer": "كسر:فلق",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 9,
    "question": "سجايا:صفات",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "أصحاب:رفقاء",
      "مواقف:ذكريات"
    ],
    "answer": "أصحاب:رفقاء",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 10,
    "question": "كرم:بذل( كرم:عطاء)",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "مال:عطاء",
      "صدقة:أجر",
      "معلم:طالب",
      "تؤدة:حلم"
    ],
    "answer": "تؤدة:حلم",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 11,
    "question": "قفل:غلق",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "يعوم:يسبح"
    ],
    "answer": "يعوم:يسبح",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 12,
    "question": "انتخاب:انتقاء",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "غش:اختبار",
      "هلُّم:أقبل",
      "انتقد:استفاد",
      "خلف:أمام"
    ],
    "answer": "هلُّم:أقبل",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 13,
    "question": "انتخاب:انتقاء ( اصطفاء:انتخاب )",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "خلف:أمام",
      "انتقاد:استفاد",
      "أقبِل:هَلُم",
      "منتخب:فريق"
    ],
    "answer": "أقبِل:هَلُم",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 14,
    "question": "متعالي:متكبر",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "إعلان:إظهار",
      "جهد:فلاح",
      "هدية:محبة"
    ],
    "answer": "إعلان:إظهار",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 15,
    "question": "تعالي:تكبر",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "إعلان:إظهار",
      "مصارعة:قوة",
      "بقاء:فناء"
    ],
    "answer": "إعلان:إظهار",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 16,
    "question": "متكبر:متعالى",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "سيف:حسام"
    ],
    "answer": "سيف:حسام",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 17,
    "question": "حسرة:ندامة",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "مفسد:مخرب",
      "طفل:رضيع"
    ],
    "answer": "مفسد:مخرب",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 18,
    "question": "جليًا:ظاهراً",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "سعادة:شعور",
      "هزبر:أسد"
    ],
    "answer": "هزبر:أسد",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 19,
    "question": "جلاء:ظهور",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "رغبة:رهبة",
      "شاق:كثير",
      "رضى:قبول",
      "سهر:أرق"
    ],
    "answer": "رضى:قبول",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 20,
    "question": "دجى:ظلمة",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "زوال:إشراق",
      "جلاء:وضوح",
      "ليل:نهار",
      "غبش:لمعان"
    ],
    "answer": "جلاء:وضوح",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 21,
    "question": "ضعف:وهن",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "استقرار:ثبات",
      "نبض:حياة"
    ],
    "answer": "استقرار:ثبات",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 22,
    "question": "احتدم:اشتد",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "حفاوة:احتفال",
      "التمس(تلمس):تشبث",
      "بعث:حث",
      "اجتهاد:....."
    ],
    "answer": "حفاوة:احتفال",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 23,
    "question": "خلود:أبدية",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "حب:وُد",
      "كرم:ضيف"
    ],
    "answer": "حب:وُد",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 24,
    "question": "ساير:وافق",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "صافح:سامح",
      "استيطان:خوف",
      "دعم:ساند",
      "أقبل:تقبل"
    ],
    "answer": "دعم:ساند",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 25,
    "question": "اتقان:جودة",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "اثبات شخصية:بطاقة",
      "كتب:قرأ",
      "صاروخ:اطلاق",
      "بداية:نهاية"
    ],
    "answer": "اثبات شخصية:بطاقة",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 26,
    "question": "أذعن:خضع",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "كلل:تعب",
      "أظهر:أخفى (أبان:أخفى)"
    ],
    "answer": "كلل:تعب",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 27,
    "question": "إذعان:إطاعة",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "اظهار:اخفاء",
      "ابتهاج:سرور",
      "زهو:تواضع"
    ],
    "answer": "ابتهاج:سرور",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 28,
    "question": "علاقة:ارتباط",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "مودة:محبة",
      "رحم:وصل"
    ],
    "answer": "مودة:محبة",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 29,
    "question": "علاقة:ارتباط",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "رحمة:مودة",
      "كرم:نبل",
      "سماحة:ود(صله:أقارب)",
      "عطاء:بذل"
    ],
    "answer": "عطاء:بذل",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 30,
    "question": "نظر:شاهد",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "فكر:يتخيل",
      "حدّث:كلّم"
    ],
    "answer": "حدّث:كلّم",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 31,
    "question": "أغلال:قيود",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "منح:هبات",
      "سجن:محكمة"
    ],
    "answer": "منح:هبات",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 32,
    "question": "انبرى:تصدي",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "تعقد:تربط",
      "كبير:صغير",
      "اعترض:وافق",
      "هشيم:حطام"
    ],
    "answer": "هشيم:حطام",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 33,
    "question": "انبرى:تصدى",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "تقدم:تراجع",
      "حارب:قاتل",
      "اعترض:وافق",
      "اتفق:اختلف"
    ],
    "answer": "حارب:قاتل",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 34,
    "question": "أصنام:أوثان",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "ماء:آبار",
      "رماح:سيوف",
      "دروب:طرق",
      "جار:رفيق"
    ],
    "answer": "دروب:طرق",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 35,
    "question": "ماهر:حاذق",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "جودة:جدية",
      "ميل:انحراف",
      "ساهِر:ليل",
      "بخل:حِرّص"
    ],
    "answer": "ميل:انحراف",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 36,
    "question": "السراب:الوهم",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "الصدى:الصوت",
      "السرقة:الجريمة",
      "القمر:الضوء",
      "الحلم:الخيال"
    ],
    "answer": "الحلم:الخيال",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 37,
    "question": "جنّة:اختفاء",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "فلاة:صحراء",
      "شروق غروب",
      "اقتصاد:ازدهار",
      "عواء:ذئب"
    ],
    "answer": "فلاة:صحراء",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  },
  {
    "question_number": 38,
    "question": "دعم:سند",
    "type": "اختيار",
    "choices": [
      "مصافحة:صلح ( تصالح)"
    ],
    "answer": "مصافحة:صلح ( تصالح)",
    "exam": "الاختبار الثالث (تناظر لفظي)\nدورة المحوسب 2025",
    "category": "التناظر اللفظي"
  }
]